Guide to the Marty Rosenbluth papers, 1980-2006 and undated RL.01110
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Marty Rosenbluth papers
1980-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Rosenbluth, Marty
RL.01110
12 Linear Feet 12,000 items
Marty Rosenbluth was Amnesty International's area specialist for Israel/Occupied Territories in the 1980s. He is also an independent documentary film-maker. The Marty Rosenbluth papers include publications, reports, case studies, press-releases, mailings, communications, leaflets, audiovisual recordings, and ephemera created by Palestinian and Israeli human rights groups. These groups include Al-Haq (Law in the Service of Man), Badil, B'Tselem, Hamoked (Center for the Defense of the Individual), Public Committee Against Torture in Israel, The West Bank Data Base Project, and Alternative Information Center. The papers also feature materials from Palestinian trade unions and United States-based solidarity groups, as well as unofficial, locally published first-person reports of events and conditions in the Occupied Territories.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Marty Rosenbluth papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in December 2006.
Biographical Note
Marty Rosenbluth was Amnesty International's area specialist for Israel/Occupied Territories in the 1980s. He is also an independent documentary film-maker.
Collection Overview
The Marty Rosenbluth papers include publications, reports, case studies, press-releases, mailings, communications, leaflets, audiovisual recordings, and ephemera created by Palestinian and Israeli human rights groups. These groups include Al-Haq (Law in the Service of Man), Badil, B'Tselem, Hamoked (Center for the Defense of the Individual), Public Committee Against Torture in Israel, The West Bank Data Base Project, and Alternative Information Center. The papers also feature materials from Palestinian trade unions and United States-based solidarity groups, as well as unofficial, locally published first-person reports of events and conditions in the Occupied Territories.
Labor unions -- Palestine; Human Rights -- Middle East; Press releases; Land settlement -- Gaza Strip; Human Rights -- Palestine; Land settlement -- Government policy -- Israel; Human Rights -- Israel; Land tenure -- Palestine; Land settlement -- Palestine; Israel -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Acquisition of territory -- Israel; West Bank -- Politics and government -- 20th century; CD-ROMs; Gaza Strip -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Audiocassettes; Videocassettes; DVDs; Population maps; Human Rights -- West Bank; Human Rights -- Gaza Strip; Human rights workers; Human rights advocacy; Ephemera; Land tenure -- Israel; Legal documents; Moked la-haganat ha-perat (Jerusalem); Human Rights Archive (Duke University); Law in the Service of Man (Organization: Ram Allah); Be-tselem (Organization: Jerusalem); Hamoked Center for the Defense of the Individual (Jerusalem); Rosenbluth, Marty; West Bank Data Base Project
- B'Tselem Series, 1990-2005
  - Printed material, 1990-2005; 1-7 of 11 folders (Box 1)
  - Printed material, 1990-2005; 8-11 of 11 folders (Box 2)
  - Human rights reports, 1994-2004 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1995-2005; 3 folders (Box 2)
- Palestine Human Rights Organizations Series, 1983-2003
  - Adalah the Legal Center for Arab Minority Rights in Israel, 1998-2002 (Box 3)
  - Badil, 2000-2001; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Birzeit University, 1983-1989 (Box 3)
  - Gaza Community Mental Health Programme, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - International Center for Peace in the Middle East, 1983,1985; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - The Jerusalem Media and Communication Centre, 1989-1996 (Box 3)
  - LAW - the Palestine Society for the Protection of Human Rights and the Environment, 1997,1999 (Box 3)
  - Palestine Human Rights Information Center, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
  - Palestine human rights publications, 1985-2003; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Palestine human rights publications by individuals, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Palestine human rights, academic journals, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Palestine human rights, various communications, 1984-1997 and undated (Box 4)
  - The Palestinian Human Rights Monitoring Group, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Public Committee Against Torture in Israel, 1999-2002; 2 folders (Box 4)
- Al-Haq Series, 1980-2003
  - Printed material, 1980-2003; 7 folders (Box 5)
  - "Human Rights Focus", 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Various publications, 1994, 2003 and undated (Box 6)
  - Newsletters, press releases, 1984-1988 and undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
- Hamoked Series, 1997-2006
  - Printed material, 1997-2006; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Annual report, 2000 (Box 6)
- West Bank Data Project Series, 1983-1998
  - Printed material, 1983-1990; 2 folders (Box 6)
- Alternative Information Center, 1986-1998
  - Miscellaneous publications, 1988, 1994, 1997 (Box 7)
  - "New from Within", 1986-1998; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - "The Other Front", 1988-1992 (Box 7)
- Foreign and U.S.-based Solidarity Groups Series, 1970-2003 and undated
  - Center for Policy Analysis on Palestine, 1994-1997 (Box 7)
  - Committee to Protect Journalists, 1988, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Middle East peace groups, 1984-1997, and undated (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous communications and mailings, 1986, 1999, and undated (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous fliers and pamphlets, 1996 and undated (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous publications, 1974-2003; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - North American Coordinating Committee for NGOs on the Question of Palestine, 1996-1998 (Box 8)
  - Palestine and the U.N., 1997-1999, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Physicians for Human Rights, 1996-1997 (Box 8)
  - Tour and trip reports, 1983, 1996 (Box 8)
  - United Nations - Division for Palestinian Rights, 1995-1998 (Box 8)
- Research Files Series, 1970-2003 and undated
  - AFL-CIO and foreign policy, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Council of Jewish Communities in Judea, Samara, and Gaza, 1985, 1990-1992 (Box 8)
  - Israel Defense Forces - orders files, 1982-1989 (Box 8)
  - Israel Defense Forces - prosecution files, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Israel foreign policy, 1984, undated (Box 8)
  - Israel - tourism, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Israeli militarism, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Jewish student activism, 1979, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Labor party and Arabs, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Labor - pro-Israeli, 1988,1989,1992,undated (Box 9)
  - Labor rights - Generalized System of Preferences, 1988-1990, and undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Land, agriculture, settlements, 1978-1995 (Box 9)
  - Lands and settlements, 1980-1991; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Lands and settlements - real estate brochures, 1991, undated (Box 9)
  - Lands and settlements - water, 1986, 1987, undated (Box 9)
  - Left-wing publications and propaganda, 1970, 1983, 1993, undated (Box 9)
  - Palestine solidarity movement, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Palestine trade and labor unions, 1988 and undated (Box 9)
  - PLO - Central Election Commission, 1996 (Box 9)
  - PLO publications, 1989-1997 (Box 9)
  - Progressive Student Network, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Pro-Israeli Christians, 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Pro-Israeli publications, 1975-1983, undated (Box 9)
  - Research notes - justice system and taxation, undated (Box 9)
  - State of Israel - government publications, 1973, 1988-2003 (Box 9)
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 2006 and undated
  Conditions Governing Access note
  [Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.]
  - 16 videocassettes, 4 DVDs, 1 CD-ROM, and 1 audiocassette on social conditions and other issues surrounding Israel and Palestine. (Box 10)
- Oversize Materials, 1982-2006 and undated, 2 oversize folders, 1 flat box
  - Publications from B'Tselem, Palestinian human rights organizations, and foreign-based solidarity groups, 1983-2006, 3 oversize folders (Box 11)
  - Two maps of occupation and dislocation of Palestinian settlements, map and welcome brochure for Russian emigres, 1982, 2000, 1989 (Box 11, Folder OF-1)
  - Al-Haq political poster, 2004 (Box 11, Folder OF-2)
  - Posters concerning human rights in the Israel/Palestine conflict, political movements in Latin America, and film screenings and film festivals related to human rights, 1977-1997 and undated (Box 11, Folder OF-3)
  - Larger posters concerning human rights in the Israel/Palestine conflict, 1999 and undated (Box 11, Folder OF-4)
  - Newspapers quoting Rosenbluth, 1982-2006 (Box 11, Folder OF-5-6)